<Document>
# Medicine

## The Brain
<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="OrganHumanBrain" Caption="Human Brain" />
</Box>

Everything in a patient's body depends on the brain.
[color=#00d3b8][bold]As long as the patient's brain is not dead, the patient is alive.[/bold][/color]
Everything else in their body is responsible for keeping its brain alive.
The more an injury threatens your patient's brain, the more important it is to treat.

[color=#00d3b8][bold]Once a brain dies, it is dead, and the body cannot be rescuitated.[/bold][/color]

A patient's brain requires adequate saturation (oxygenation for most species) in the bloodstream to survive.
[color=#00d3b8][bold]The primary goal in medical care is to ensure the brain has adequate saturation.[/bold][/color]

## Blood Saturation

Blood saturation is the primary measure for how satiated a patient's brain is.

Blood saturation is affected by:
- [color=cyan]Blood volume[/color]: Blood can be restored with saline for most species, or blood bags.
- [color=cyan]Breathable air[/color]: Ensure the patient can breathe. Dexalin (plus) can be used to artificially oxygenate the bloodstream.
- [color=cyan]Blood circulation[/color]: The heart is responsible for circulating blood around your patient's body. CPR can be administered if the patient's heart has stopped, followed by surgical intervention as soon as possible.

## The Heart

<Box>
  <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="OrganHumanHeart" Caption="Human Heart" />
</Box>

The heart is responsible for blood circulation.

[color=#00d3b8][bold]If a patient's heart has stopped, they are priority number one.[/bold][/color]

Blood circulation increases with heartrate, and decreases with heart damage, coming to near-zero if the heart stops.

The heart will increase its heartrate in response to pain, lack of access to breathable air, and lowered blood volume.

The heart will stop from:
- [color=cyan]Ventricular tachycardia[/color]: Excessively high pulse can cause the patient's heart to stop, usually from pain. Administer painkillers and inaprovaline before restarting the heart.
- [color=cyan]Hypovolemia[/color]: If a patient loses too much blood, their heart will stop. Stop bleeding and restore blood levels before restarting the heart.
- [color=cyan]Accumulated damage[/color]: If a patient's heart accumulates too much damage, it will stop. Surgical intervention will be required before restarting the heart.

The heart can be restarted using a defibrillator.

If the heart cannot be restarted, medical professionals and other crew alike can administer CPR to ensure blood circulation.
</Document>

<!--
  This Source Code Form is subject to the terms of the Mozilla Public
  License, v. 2.0. If a copy of the MPL was not distributed with this
  file, You can obtain one at http://mozilla.org/MPL/2.0/.
-->
