<Document>
  # Allulalo

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobAllulalo" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  [color=#ffa500]Caution! This species has multiple severely limiting game mechanics.[/color]

  Allulalo are a reclusive species of sauropods native to the IMP-sector outer nebulas. They are rarely seen, preferring to conceal their cities deep inside asteroid fields and cloak their ships with stealth fields.
  
  Their small stature makes them remarkably fast on their feet, but the unusual, pentafurcated beak they use for manipulating in the place of traditional "hands" [color=#ffa500]prevents them from weilding any large weaponry.[/color] Their height also causes them trouble with NT standard interfaces, often [color=#ffa500]needing to stand on chairs and tables or use anti-gravity technology to use large devices.[/color]

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="ComputerAlert" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="VendingMachineCigs" Caption=""/>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="Autolathe" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  # Biology

  Allulalo possess no damage weaknesses or strengths, but are[color=#ffa500]25% more vulnerable to stuns, and their low bodymass causes them to be thrown farther by impacts[/color].

  It is easy to underestimate Allulalo due to these drawbacks, but they have a major strength: [color=#1e90ff]They are a large margin faster than any other known terrestrial humanoids[/color].

  Allulalo are also in unique posession of a highly methylated bloodstream. Due to this, [color=#1e90ff]their blood naturally evaporates on its own[/color], as well as making them [color=#1e90ff]remarkably heavyweight drinkers[/color] for their bodyweight.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="DrinkAbsintheBottleFull" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  # Physical Strength

  Allulalo have naturally lower bodymass due to their stature, and as of such have difficulty dragging things larger than themselves. Their smaller size does, however, [color=#1e90ff]allow them to pilot VIMs[/color].
  Their talons, despite lacking dexterity, are capable of functioning as crude weapons, dealing slash damage.

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MechVimBattery" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  ## Allulalo Naming Conventions

  Allulalo names are comprised of two parts. Their "First name" is similar in function to a human's, while their "Last name" is a conjunction of the first syllables of both of their parent's names.

  - [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] Halio Hera-Nofa
  - [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] Sadita Ona-Rona
  - [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] Unira Lota-Pota
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Waga Baga-Bobo
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Pete, Pee-Pee
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Benry Pasa-Porta

</Document>
