<Document>
  # Ungu

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="MobUngu" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

  [color=#ffa500]Caution! This species has a limiting game mechanic.[/color]

  <Box>
    <GuideEntityEmbed Entity="WheatBushel" Caption=""/>
  </Box>

## Physiology

  Ungu are strong, hardy creatures from a primarily cold planet, notably taller and bulkier than other NT-employed species. As such, they are [color=#ffa500] unable to wear hardsuits,[/color] having to make do with 'softsuits' and added winter gear.

  They take [color=#1e90ff] less damage from the cold and physical attacks, which, combined with a higher health pool, [/color] makes them formidable even in emergency EVA.

  They tend to move slightly slower than other species, but when charging to attack, they become noticeably faster, although they risk hurting themselves by hitting walls or other obstacles.

  Ungu's unarmed attacks are slow but [color=#1e90ff]hit hard, knocking targets flying and dealing damage to structures.[/color]



 ## Diet

  Ungu's are unable to consume meat, eating primarily fruit and vegetables along with any wheat or kudzu they can get ahold of.

  Due to their double stomachs, they require a lot of food to be full but digest slowly.

 ## Ungu Naming Conventions

  The typical Ungus name is three letters long, acting as a translation of the short bark-like sounds they use to address each other casually. The titles they add to their names are a shorthand for traditional greeting stories, as historically when meeting someone it is considered polite between Ungu to exchange a story about an important aspect of yourself or your life experiences.

  Ungu may often change their titles to reflect significant events or life circumstances. "Negative" titles aren't seen as shameful but rather as a sign of strength to move past something troubling or accept oneself.


  - [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] Mob, Who Mixed Brutes
  - [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] Bub, Who Knows
  - [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] Ohe, The fool.
  - [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] Kaz, Haunted
  - [color=#449944]Acceptable:[/color] Slo, The Steady Hauler
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Bessie, The Cow
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Thog, Dont Caare
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Big, The Cat
  - [color=#994444]Bad:[/color] Benry, From Half Life VR But The AI Is Self Aware

</Document>
